<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Review on Nono Blogs</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/categories/review/</link><description>Recent content in Review on Nono Blogs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 10:03:40 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/categories/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A brief share on using trae</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/22/a-brief-share-on-using-trae/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 10:03:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/22/a-brief-share-on-using-trae/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This lengthy post was published on 2025-07-22; at the moment trae&amp;rsquo;s feature completeness and performance remain poor. It may improve later, so feel free to try it for yourself and trust your own experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As common sense dictates, the first employees shape a company’s culture and products, forming a deep-rooted foundation that is hard to change and also somewhat intangible; my sharing is for reference only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="ui-design"&gt;UI Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trae’s interface has nice aesthetics, with layout / color / font tweaks over the original version, and it looks great visually. The logic is fairly clear as well; in this area I have no suggestions to offer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Huawei Field Notes: An Insider's Reading of Organisational DNA</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/09/huawei-field-notes-an-insiders-reading-of-organisational-dna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 17:55:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/09/huawei-field-notes-an-insiders-reading-of-organisational-dna/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;After three years at Huawei I left for personal reasons, leaving me with a distinct feel for its culture. I now attempt, with several concrete cases, to give an insider’s structured rundown of the company’s characteristics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-management-dna-the-fusion-of-technical-genes-and-commercial-acumen"&gt;1. Management DNA: the fusion of technical genes and commercial acumen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei’s leadership pipeline shows a unique hybrid profile:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical grounding&lt;/strong&gt;: core managers nearly all have R&amp;amp;D backgrounds, their genes shape decision logic and technology road-maps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managerial evolution&lt;/strong&gt;: as the organisation grew, leaders gradually transformed from technical specialists into strategists, creating an “engineer-style management philosophy”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dialectical tension&lt;/strong&gt;: purely technical talents must leap from deep expertise to system-level oversight, so career transformation demands twin up-skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2-execution-culture-organisational-efficiency-under-high-pressure"&gt;2. Execution culture: organisational efficiency under high pressure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei’s outcome-oriented execution system is a double-edged sword.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>GitHub Copilot Paid Models Comparison</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/03/04/github-copilot-paid-models-comparison/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 11:22:40 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/03/04/github-copilot-paid-models-comparison/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://img1.techfetch.dev/blog/202503041205012.png" alt="7 models"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub Copilot currently offers 7 models:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claude 3.5 Sonnet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claude 3.7 Sonnet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Claude 3.7 Sonnet Thinking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gemini 2.0 Flash&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPT-4o&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;o1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;o3-mini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The official documentation lacks an introduction to these seven models. This post briefly describes their ratings across various domains to highlight their specific strengths, helping readers switch to the most suitable model when tackling particular problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="model-comparison"&gt;Model Comparison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multi-dimensional comparison table based on publicly available evaluation data (some figures are estimates or adjusted from multiple sources), covering three key metrics: coding (SWE-Bench Verified), math (AIME’24), and reasoning (GPQA Diamond).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Community Rules Analysis</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/research/community-rules-analysis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 14:41:23 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/research/community-rules-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Community Rules Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cross-Platform Content Publishing Tool — A Review of "蚁小二"</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/05/09/cross-platform-content-publishing-tool-a-review-of-%E8%9A%81%E5%B0%8F%E4%BA%8C/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 20:47:38 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/05/09/cross-platform-content-publishing-tool-a-review-of-%E8%9A%81%E5%B0%8F%E4%BA%8C/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="foreword"&gt;Foreword&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, I’ve wanted to write a bit to diversify my income, so I scouted around the various creator platforms, hoping to earn something—if not cash, then at least some coins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Putting aside the platforms themselves, writing requires a bit of brainpower, and crafting articles isn’t easy. Naturally, I don’t want to send each piece to only one outlet. When you publish on multiple platforms, however, you run into one very annoying problem: repeating the same task over and over again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jianshu Writing Experience</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/05/09/jianshu-writing-experience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 12:28:43 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/05/09/jianshu-writing-experience/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Jianshu&amp;rsquo;s writing experience is only slightly better than Notepad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="minimalist-note-management"&gt;Minimalist Note Management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the article-editing page, with only two levels of abstraction:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;notebook list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;note list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/05/09/QaCNwOghDi6b7xu.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fewer levels are both advantageous and problematic. Simple operations reduce cognitive load, yet they will eventually increase an author&amp;rsquo;s overhead in managing articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="difficult-image-uploading"&gt;Difficult Image Uploading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For eight whole years, Jianshu has still not solved the external-image upload issue.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/05/09/nxkTBGpo3KDjtsh.png" alt="https://www.jianshu.com/p/acb660ddc619"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;External linking only fails sometimes, and many image hosts allow empty or any referer—Jianshu doesn&amp;rsquo;t even try, claiming local upload is the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; way. One wonders if the operators have ever tried writing on other platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>