<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Game-Theory on Nono Blogs</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/tags/game-theory/</link><description>Recent content in Game-Theory on Nono Blogs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 17:35:19 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/tags/game-theory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Third-party Library Pitfalls</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/third-party-library-pitfalls/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 17:35:19 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/third-party-library-pitfalls/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"&gt; Third-party library pitfalls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today we talked about a vulnerability in a recently released third-party logging library that can be exploited with minimal effort to execute remote commands. A logging library and remote command execution seem completely unrelated, yet over-engineered third-party libraries are everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more code I read, the more I feel that a lot of open-source code is of very poor quality—regardless of how many k-stars it has. Stars represent needs, not engineering skill.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Game Theory</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/notes/game-theory/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 12:10:23 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/notes/game-theory/</guid><description/></item><item><title>OKR Pitfalls and Boons</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2023/06/27/okr-pitfalls-and-boons/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 15:33:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2023/06/27/okr-pitfalls-and-boons/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="okr-pitfalls-and-boons"&gt;OKR Pitfalls and Boons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2009, Harvard Business School published a paper titled &lt;em&gt;Goals Gone Wild&lt;/em&gt;. Using a series of examples, it explained “the destructive side of over-pursuing goals”: the Ford Pinto’s exploding gas tank, Sears Auto Centers’ rampant overcharging, Enron’s wildly inflated sales targets, and the 1996 Mount Everest disaster that killed eight people. The authors warn that goals are “a prescription drug that must be handled with care and monitored closely.” They even state: “Because of excessive focus, unethical behavior, greater risk taking and decreased cooperation and intrinsic motivation, goals create systematic problems inside organizations.” The downsides of goal-setting may cancel out the benefits—that was the thesis.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>