<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Security on Nono Blogs</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/tags/security/</link><description>Recent content in Security on Nono Blogs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Attack Methods Against Model-Relay Services</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/11/attack-methods-against-model-relay-services/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 11:52:10 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/11/attack-methods-against-model-relay-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>Avoiding public routers—especially free Wi-Fi—has become common sense in recent years, yet many people still don’t understand &lt;em>why&lt;/em>, leaving them vulnerable to new variants of the same trick.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to Anthropic’s corporate policy, users in China cannot conveniently access its services; because its technology is cutting-edge, many still want to try. This created the “Claude relay” business.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, we must realize this business is &lt;strong>not sustainable&lt;/strong>. Unlike other ordinary internet services, simply using a generic VPN will &lt;em>not&lt;/em> satisfy Anthropic’s blocks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Risks of AI Model-Relay Services</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/10/the-risks-of-ai-model-relay-services/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 20:28:04 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/10/the-risks-of-ai-model-relay-services/</guid><description>&lt;p>Lately, in the comment threads on AI-related posts, you’ll see a flood of low-quality ads touting “cheap Claude Code relay” services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The business model is simple: Claude Code lets you supply your own API endpoint and key, including any vendor that’s OpenAI-compatible. That’s all there is to it. Pull in a bit of Claude’s traffic, mix in some Qwen tokens, and sell the blended soup—who’s going to notice?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Those who only want to make a quick buck are the timid ones; how much can they really earn? The truly valuable assets are where you keep your savings and your critical data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Avoid Getting Doxxed</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/03/19/how-to-avoid-getting-doxxed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 16:54:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/03/19/how-to-avoid-getting-doxxed/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="fragmented-information-is-easily-pieced-together">Fragmented information is easily pieced together&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Personal information is dispersed and sensitive—easy to overlook. Yet the internet is not a safe harbor; countless people can stitch this information together using search engines and other tools.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Take the xhs community as an example: users there have comparatively weak network-security awareness and often share the meaning behind their passwords and the scenarios in which they are used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://img1.techfetch.dev/blog/202503191707446.png" alt="xhs search results">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Searching for “password meaning” reveals a flood of users openly displaying their passwords and their explanations.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Offense &amp; Defense</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/attack-and-defense/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 15:57:34 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/attack-and-defense/</guid><description/></item><item><title>snort</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/snort/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 19:03:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/snort/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> snort&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="snort">Snort&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.snort.org/">https://www.snort.org/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Protect your network with the world&amp;rsquo;s most powerful Open Source detection software.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>What is Snort?&lt;/strong>
Snort is the foremost Open Source Intrusion Prevention System (IPS) in the world.
Snort IPS uses a series of rules that help define malicious network activity and
uses those rules to find packets that match against them and generates alerts for users.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Snort can be deployed inline to stop these packets, as well.
Snort has three primary uses: As a packet sniffer like tcpdump, as a packet logger —
which is useful for network traffic debugging, or it can be used as a full-blown network intrusion prevention system.
Snort can be downloaded and configured for personal and business use alike.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Trustworthy Design</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/trustworthy-design/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:49:18 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/trustworthy-design/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="security-architecture-and-design-principles">Security Architecture and Design Principles&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="the-three-security-elements-and-security-design-principles">The Three Security Elements and Security Design Principles&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Integrity&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Availability&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Confidentiality&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="open-design-principle">Open Design Principle&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Open Design&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The design should not be secret; open designs are more secure.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Security does not rely on secrecy.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="fail-safe-defaults-principle">Fail-Safe Defaults Principle&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Fail-safe defaults&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Access decisions are based on &amp;ldquo;permit&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;deny&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>By default, access is denied; protection mechanisms merely identify the subset of allowed actions.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Safe failure: any complex system must have an emergency safety mechanism after functional failure; also be careful with error messages and logs to prevent information leakage.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Safe by default: in its initial state, the default configuration is secure by providing the least services and systems necessary for maximal safety.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="separation-of-privilege-principle">Separation of Privilege Principle&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Separation of Privilege&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Huawei Trust Concept</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/huawei-trust-concept/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:49:02 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/huawei-trust-concept/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Huawei Trust Concept&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Security: The product has strong anti-attack capabilities to safeguard the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of services and data.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Resilience: When under attack, the system maintains a defined operational state (including degraded states) and has the ability to recover quickly and evolve continuously.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Privacy: Complying with privacy protection is not only a legal and regulatory requirement but also a reflection of values. Users should be able to appropriately control how their data is used. Data usage policies should be transparent to users. Users should decide when and whether to receive information according to their needs. Privacy data must be safeguarded by robust protection capabilities and mechanisms.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Huawei Intranet Security Analysis</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/huawei-intranet-security-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:48:48 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/huawei-intranet-security-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Huawei Intranet Security Analysis&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Huawei has plenty of excellent internal learning materials, and I have amassed a wealth of knowledge and experience myself; I have long wondered how to import them into my personal knowledge base. I am fully aware that these generic insights are neither confidential nor sensitive, yet the ever-present warning bells of information security make me itchy while keeping well behind the red line. After some testing, I found the company’s network-security protections hard to break. This article provides a sketchy analysis of the R&amp;amp;D yellow zone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>DDoS Defense</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/ddos-defense/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:47:44 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2024/06/28/ddos-defense/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="ddos-defense">DDoS Defense&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Denial-of-service_attack">DDoS Definition&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Two kinds of DoS attacks:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Crash the service&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Congest the network&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="attack-types">Attack Types&lt;/h2>
&lt;table>
 &lt;thead>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;th>Attack Type&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>Attack Method&lt;/th>
 &lt;th>Countermeasure&lt;/th>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/thead>
 &lt;tbody>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Distributed DoS&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Multiple independent-IP machines begin attacking simultaneously&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>1. Degrade service 2. Blacklist 3. Shut down network equipment&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Yo-yo attack&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Against services that can auto-scale resources, attacks during the small window when resources are shrinking&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Blacklist&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Application layer attacks&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Target specific functions or features; &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LAND">LAND&lt;/a> attacks fall into this category&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Blacklist&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>LANS&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Specially crafted TCP SYN packets (normally used to open a new connection) cause the target to open a null connection whose source and destination are both its own IP, continuously self-responding until it crashes. Different from SYN flood.&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Blacklist&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Advanced persistent DoS&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Anti-reconnaissance / pinpoint targets / evasion / long duration / high compute / multithreaded&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Degrade service&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>HTTP slow POST DoS&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>After creating legitimate connections, send large amounts of data at very low speed until server resources are exhausted&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Degrade service&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Challenge Collapsar (CC) attack&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Frequently send standard legitimate requests that consume heavy resources (e.g., search engines use lots of RAM)&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Degrade service, content identification&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>ICMP flood&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Mass ping / bad ping / Ping of Death (malformed ping packets)&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Degrade service&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Permanent denial-of-service attacks&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Attack on hardware&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Content identification&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Reflected attack&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Send requests to third parties, spoof source address so replies go to the real victim&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>DDoS scope&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Amplification&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Exploit some services as reflectors to magnify traffic&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>DDoS scope&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Mirai botnet&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Leverage compromised IoT devices&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>DDoS scope&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>SACK Panic&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Manipulate MSS and selective acknowledgement to cause retransmission&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Content identification&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Shrew attack&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Exploit weaknesses in TCP retransmission timeout with short synchronous bursts to disrupt TCP connections on the same link&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Timeout discard&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Slow Read attack&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Like slow POST: send legitimate requests but read extremely slowly to exhaust connection pools by advertising a very small TCP Receive Window&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Timeout disconnect, degrade service, blacklist&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>SYN flood&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Send large numbers of TCP/SYN packets, creating half-open connections&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Timeout mechanism&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>Teardrop attacks&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Send malformed IP fragments with overlapping oversized payloads to the target&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Content identification&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>TTL expiry attack&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>When packets are dropped due to TTL expiry, the router CPU must generate and send ICMP Time-Exceeded responses; generating many of these overloads the CPU&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Drop traffic&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>UPnP attack&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Based on DNS amplification, but uses a UPnP router that forwards requests from an external source while ignoring UPnP rules&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Degrade service&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>SSDP reflection&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Many devices, including home routers, have UPnP vulnerabilities that let attackers obtain replies to a spoofed target on port 1900&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Degrade service, block port&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;tr>
 &lt;td>ARP spoofing&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>Associate a MAC address with another computer or gateway (router) IP so traffic directed to the legitimate IP is rerouted to the attacker, causing DoS&lt;/td>
 &lt;td>DDoS scope&lt;/td>
 &lt;/tr>
 &lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h2 id="protective-measures">Protective Measures&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Identify attack traffic&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/security/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 15:47:23 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/security/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> _index&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Get Alibaba Cloud Edge Security Acceleration (ESA) for Free</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/08/20/get-alibaba-cloud-edge-security-acceleration-esa-for-free/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/08/20/get-alibaba-cloud-edge-security-acceleration-esa-for-free/</guid><description>&lt;p>Alibaba Cloud Edge Security Acceleration (ESA) is a comprehensive service that integrates CDN, edge security protection, and dynamic acceleration. It significantly boosts the speed and security of websites and applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article briefly explains how to claim an ESA package at no cost through official channels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The campaign is open to &lt;strong>all Alibaba Cloud users who have completed account verification&lt;/strong>. Free service credits are awarded in exchange for sharing your experience.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Security Best Practices for Personal Domains</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/01/17/security-best-practices-for-personal-domains/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 12:49:43 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/01/17/security-best-practices-for-personal-domains/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="preface">Preface&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In the Internet era, cyber attacks have become the norm. Every day, countless automated tools scan every corner of the web looking for vulnerabilities. Many believe only large corporations become targets, but due to lower attack costs and widespread tooling, any service exposed to the Internet can be attacked.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="real-world-case-analysis">Real-World Case Analysis&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="scanning-attack-example">Scanning Attack Example&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A small demo site I host on Cloudflare has only two valid URLs:
&lt;img src="https://img1.techfetch.dev/blog/202501171325208.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://weread-challenge.techfetch.dev/">https://weread-challenge.techfetch.dev/&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://weread-challenge.techfetch.dev/logs-collector">https://weread-challenge.techfetch.dev/logs-collector&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Yet it is continuously scanned.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>