<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorial on Nono Blogs</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/tags/tutorial/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorial on Nono Blogs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 18:13:08 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jqknono.com/tags/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Public Service</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/docs/public-service/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 18:13:08 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/docs/public-service/</guid><description>&lt;p>It should be noted first that household internet services in mainland China come with agreements that prohibit commercial use. In actual enforcement, whether the service is used commercially or not is not strictly monitored. However, when there are a large number of inbound HTTP/HTTPS connections (some say around 250), the service is downgraded, which causes various issues.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Therefore, if you intend to provide public services, it should be treated as commercial use. It is best to rent a VPS from a cloud service provider to host public services.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Devices</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/docs/private-service/devices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:09:08 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/docs/private-service/devices/</guid><description>&lt;p>This section discusses suitable devices for hosting home services.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hardware-platforms">Hardware Platforms&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are many options for home-use devices: retired laptops,闲置 desktops, development boards, NAS devices, soft routers, Macs, etc., all of which can host services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hardware choices in 2024 no longer need to be limited to &lt;strong>x86&lt;/strong> platforms. &lt;strong>ARM&lt;/strong> platforms have matured with advantages including low cost, sufficient performance, low power consumption, and rich ecosystems suitable for home use. Unless you must run legacy software, &lt;strong>ARM&lt;/strong> platforms are excellent choices.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>