<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Network on jqknono Blogs</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/categories/network/</link><description>Recent content in Network on jqknono Blogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jqknono.com/categories/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Comparative Technical Analysis of DoH and DoT</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/blog/2026/02/11/doh-vs-dot-comparison/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/blog/2026/02/11/doh-vs-dot-comparison/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;DNS over HTTPS (DoH) and DNS over TLS (DoT) are two common encrypted DNS transport methods that implement secure transmission of DNS queries through different protocol stacks. The DoT standard is defined by &lt;a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc7858"&gt;RFC 7858&lt;/a&gt;, while DoH is standardized by &lt;a href="https://datatracker.ietf.org/doc/html/rfc8484"&gt;DNS Queries over HTTPS (DoH)&lt;/a&gt;. Understanding the essential differences between these two technologies requires analysis starting from the network protocol hierarchy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="network-protocol-hierarchy"&gt;Network Protocol Hierarchy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern network protocol stacks adopt a layered design, with each layer providing different functions. As an application layer protocol, DNS itself is not bound to a specific transport method and can run over various bearer protocols.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is Cloudflare Completely Trustworthy?</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/blog/2025/12/02/is-cloudflare-completely-trustworthy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 08:30:50 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/blog/2025/12/02/is-cloudflare-completely-trustworthy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Cloudflare, Aliyun ESA, Tencent EdgeOne, etc., all hold domain certificates, which means they can fully inspect all traffic under the domain. They themselves are large middlemen. Their primary function is security; there are too many attackers on the internet, and choosing a large middleman has more benefits than drawbacks. Secondary functions include providing DNS, CDN, WAF, and other edge services simultaneously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Services like Cloudflare can effectively defend against DDoS, trading a slight increase in latency for protection capability, which is very cost-effective. Every site owner should directly use such services; network attacks are everywhere, no need to be optimistic, you&amp;rsquo;ll be attacked sooner or later. Some attacks exploit vulnerabilities, related to the site operator&amp;rsquo;s skill level. Other attacks aim to consume resources, like DDoS, exploiting the cost asymmetry between commercial and home networks—a kind of open conspiracy. Often, you can only fight back with money or shut down the service directly, abandoning all users, also known as black hole defense.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Record of Troubleshooting a Non-Typical Home Network Issue</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/blog/2025/11/29/%E8%AE%B0%E4%B8%80%E6%AC%A1%E9%9D%9E%E5%85%B8%E5%9E%8B%E5%AE%B6%E5%BA%AD%E7%BD%91%E7%BB%9C%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98%E6%8E%92%E6%9F%A5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 11:25:30 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/blog/2025/11/29/%E8%AE%B0%E4%B8%80%E6%AC%A1%E9%9D%9E%E5%85%B8%E5%9E%8B%E5%AE%B6%E5%BA%AD%E7%BD%91%E7%BB%9C%E9%97%AE%E9%A2%98%E6%8E%92%E6%9F%A5/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The phenomenon was that whenever the Lenovo laptop was taken out of the study room, the entire family&amp;rsquo;s internet would go down. Plugging it back into power in the study room restored the home network. The self-hosted &lt;a href="https://github.com/NullPrivate/NullPrivate"&gt;NullPrivate DNS&lt;/a&gt; occasionally interrupted, and the main PC occasionally lost connection. Later confirmed to be a switch issue; restarting the switch resolved it.
&lt;img src="https://share.jqknono.com/image/blog/44f37f2cac1dd15771546949a8d81680.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Mercury switch had been used for years without issues, but recently it required multiple restarts, drawing my attention. Either the device is aging, or the root cause might not be the switch.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>