<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Devices on Nono Blogs</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/tags/devices/</link><description>Recent content in Devices on Nono Blogs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:09:08 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/tags/devices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Devices</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/docs/private-service/devices/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 12:09:08 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/docs/private-service/devices/</guid><description>&lt;p>This section discusses suitable devices for hosting home services.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="hardware-platforms">Hardware Platforms&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are many options for home-use devices: retired laptops,闲置 desktops, development boards, NAS devices, soft routers, Macs, etc., all of which can host services.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hardware choices in 2024 no longer need to be limited to &lt;strong>x86&lt;/strong> platforms. &lt;strong>ARM&lt;/strong> platforms have matured with advantages including low cost, sufficient performance, low power consumption, and rich ecosystems suitable for home use. Unless you must run legacy software, &lt;strong>ARM&lt;/strong> platforms are excellent choices.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Device Classification</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/docs/private-service/devices/device-classification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 12:26:28 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/docs/private-service/devices/device-classification/</guid><description>&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;input disabled="" type="checkbox"> Device Classification&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Popular network devices such as NAS, soft routers, Mac minis, and traditional routers are unified as &amp;ldquo;devices&amp;rdquo;. Users don&amp;rsquo;t need to focus on their naming or physical forms, but should primarily consider four aspects: &lt;strong>processor&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>storage&lt;/strong>, &lt;strong>networking&lt;/strong>, and &lt;strong>application ecosystem&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most important consideration for processors is architecture, with &lt;strong>x86&lt;/strong> and &lt;strong>ARM&lt;/strong> being the most commonly used. Other architectures are not recommended for non-professionals due to their limited ecosystems which increase learning and usage difficulties.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>