<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Privacy Protection on jqknono Blogs</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/tags/privacy-protection/</link><description>Recent content in Privacy Protection on jqknono Blogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jqknono.com/tags/privacy-protection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How DNS Affects Your Internet Experience</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/blog/2025/10/13/dns-impact-on-browsing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/blog/2025/10/13/dns-impact-on-browsing/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="how-dns-affects-your-internet-experience"&gt;How DNS Affects Your Internet Experience&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we open a web page, watch a video, or click a link within an app, the first hop almost always lands on DNS. It acts like a telephone directory for the online world, responsible for translating human-friendly domain names into IP addresses that machines can understand. Many people attribute issues like &amp;ldquo;slow web pages, inability to open sites, or inconsistent performance&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;poor internet speed,&amp;rdquo; when in fact, a significant portion of these experience fluctuations are related to DNS resolution success rates, latency, cache hits, and privacy policies. Understanding how DNS works, its exposure points in the connection chain, and the available protection strategies can help us break down &amp;ldquo;slowness and instability&amp;rdquo; into manageable factors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Potential Security Risks of Open Source Blogs: How to Protect Personal Information from Leaks</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/blog/2025/10/11/potential-security-risks-of-open-source-blogs-how-to-protect-personal-information-from-leaks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 10:00:00 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/blog/2025/10/11/potential-security-risks-of-open-source-blogs-how-to-protect-personal-information-from-leaks/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GitHub Pages, as a free open-source blog hosting platform, is widely popular due to its convenience and cost-free nature. However, the free version requires repositories to be public to provide public access services, a feature that may lead to unexpected information leakage risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if the article content itself does not contain sensitive information, the blog&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;source code repository&lt;/strong&gt; might inadvertently leak personal privacy information. This article will explore these potential risks and provide practical solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>