<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Stop and Go on Nono Blogs</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/notes/wandering/</link><description>Recent content in Stop and Go on Nono Blogs</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 17:55:59 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/notes/wandering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An Attempt at an Objective Review of Huawei</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/09/an-attempt-at-an-objective-review-of-huawei/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 17:55:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/09/an-attempt-at-an-objective-review-of-huawei/</guid><description>&lt;p>After working at Huawei for three years, I left for personal reasons and gained a bit of insight into its culture. Here, I simply share some of my shallow reflections.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="leadership-traits">Leadership Traits&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Many Huawei leaders come from a technical background, but I don&amp;rsquo;t consider them purely technical people—rather, they behave more like politicians. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to judge whether that&amp;rsquo;s good or bad, but if you&amp;rsquo;re a &amp;ldquo;pure&amp;rdquo; engineer, working at Huawei may leave you feeling slighted somewhat.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Huawei Field Notes: An Insider's Reading of Organisational DNA</title><link>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/09/huawei-field-notes-an-insiders-reading-of-organisational-dna/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 17:55:59 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://blog.jqknono.com/en-us/blog/2025/07/09/huawei-field-notes-an-insiders-reading-of-organisational-dna/</guid><description>&lt;p>After three years at Huawei I left for personal reasons, leaving me with a distinct feel for its culture. I now attempt, with several concrete cases, to give an insider’s structured rundown of the company’s characteristics.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="1-management-dna-the-fusion-of-technical-genes-and-commercial-acumen">1. Management DNA: the fusion of technical genes and commercial acumen&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Huawei’s leadership pipeline shows a unique hybrid profile:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Technical grounding&lt;/strong>: core managers nearly all have R&amp;amp;D backgrounds, their genes shape decision logic and technology road-maps.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Managerial evolution&lt;/strong>: as the organisation grew, leaders gradually transformed from technical specialists into strategists, creating an “engineer-style management philosophy”.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Dialectical tension&lt;/strong>: purely technical talents must leap from deep expertise to system-level oversight, so career transformation demands twin up-skills.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="2-execution-culture-organisational-efficiency-under-high-pressure">2. Execution culture: organisational efficiency under high pressure&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Huawei’s outcome-oriented execution system is a double-edged sword.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>